Guide to the Yehuda Amichai Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1944-1999; Series I; 5.63; (14 boxes)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - University of California Press, 1994, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 565)
    - University of Cincinnati, 1974, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 566)
    - University of Iowa, 1979, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 567)
    - University of Natal, 1997-1999 (Box 12, Folder 568)
    - University of Texas, 1982 Nov 29 (Box 12, Folder 569)
    - University of Utah. Middle East Center, 1987 Nov 4 (Box 12, Folder 570)
    - Upper Canada College, 1993 Aug 18 (Box 12, Folder 571)
    - "V" General, 1974-1995, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 572)
    - Vancouver (B.C.). City Council, 1995 May 12 (Box 12, Folder 573)
    - Vasovic, Nebojsa, 1991 Jan 18 (Box 12, Folder 574)
    - Verband Fränkischer Schriftsteller, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 575)
    - Verse, 1995 Jul 16 (Box 12, Folder 576)
    - Viking, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 577)
    - Voices Israel, 1979 Jul 29 (Box 12, Folder 578)
    - Volkshochschule Aachen, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 579)
    - Vuelta, 1991, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 580)
    - "W" General, 1973-1995, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 581)
    - W. W. Norton & Company, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 582)
    - Wallmann, Jürgen Peter, 1992 Apr 24 (Box 12, Folder 583)
    - Waring, Belle, 1989 Dec 21 (Box 12, Folder 584)
    - The Watershed Foundation, 1980-1982 (Box 12, Folder 585)
    - Weber, Doron, 1988 Jun 10 (Box 12, Folder 586)
    - Weiss, Shevah, 1995 Nov 28 (Box 12, Folder 587)
    - Weiss, Ted, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 588)
    - Weissbort, Daniel, 1965-1990 (Box 12, Folder 589)
    - Werle, Simon, 1968 May 6 (Box 12, Folder 590)
    - Werner Söderström Osakeyhtiö, 1997 Dec 16 (Box 12, Folder 591)
    - Wesleyan University, 1991 Dec 13 (Box 12, Folder 592)
    - Whitney Humanities Center, 1994 Sep 5 (Box 12, Folder 593)
    - Wieseltier, Leon, 1983-1985, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 594)
    - Williams & Connolly, 1996 Nov (Box 12, Folder 595)
    - Williams [College?], 1997 Nov 12 (Box 12, Folder 596)
    - Wiltmann, Ingrid, 1995-1998 (Box 12, Folder 597)
    - Wittstock, Alfred, 1991 Dec 14 (Box 12, Folder 598)
    - Wolheim, William, 1988 Jul 18 (Box 12, Folder 599)
    - World Union of Jewish Students, 1992-1996 (Box 12, Folder 600)
    - World Zionist Organization, 1981-1996 (Box 12, Folder 601)
    - Würzburg (Germany), 1969-1994 (Box 12, Folder 602)
      Includes photographs of Amichai
    - "X" General, n.y. Jan 11 (Box 12, Folder 603)
    - "Y" General, 1975-1997, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 604)
    - Yaakov, Zeev, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 605)
    - Yad Yitshak Ben-Tsevi, 1997 Dec 1 (Box 12, Folder 606)
    - Yardeni, Ada, 1994 May 1 (Box 12, Folder 607)
    - Yediot aharonot (Firm), 1989-1997 (Box 12, Folder 608)
    - Yedlin, Aharon, 1975 Dec 14 (Box 12, Folder 609)
    - Yehoshua, Abraham B., 1968-1995, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 610)
    - Yerushalmi, Yosef Hayim, 1994 May 24 (Box 12, Folder 611)
    - Yonathan, Nathan, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 612)
    - Young Judaea, Inc., 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 613)
    - Young, Mimi, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 614)
    - "Z" General, 1995-1999 (Box 12, Folder 615)
    - Zach, Nathan, 1966-1982 (Box 12, Folder 616)
    - Zamir, Yehoshua, 1991 Jan 30 (Box 12, Folder 617)
      Includes photographs, drawings, and poems
    - Zheng, Jusheng, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 618)
    - Ziff, Joel [David?], 1995 Nov 5 (Box 12, Folder 619)
    - Zimmermann, Heidy, 1997 Dec 23 (Box 12, Folder 620)
    - First name only, 1966-1997, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 621-624)
    - First name only, 1966-1997, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 625-626)
    - Unidentified, 1971-1998, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 627-629)
    - Empty envelopes, 1981-1994, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 630-631)
  - THIRD PARTY
    - To Idit Amichai
      - Beichman, Janin, 1993 Sep 19 (Box 14, Folder 632)
      - Kanaseki, Hisao, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 633)
      - Kawakami, Yasanori, 1993 Feb 24 (Box 14, Folder 634)
    - To and From Joseph Cohen
      - Abner Stein, 1989-1990 (Box 14, Folder 635)
      - Viking, 1989 Nov 27 (Box 14, Folder 636)
    - To and From Makhon le-tirgum sifrut Ivrit (Israel)
      - Actes Sud (Firm), 1993 Jul 19 (Box 14, Folder 637)
      - Cohen, Doron, 1993 Mar 22 (Box 14, Folder 638)
      - Dialogo Mediterraneo, 1993 Oct 27 (Box 14, Folder 639)
      - Heiskanen, Teppo, 1997 Sep 14 (Box 14, Folder 640)
      - Liepman AG, 1983, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 641)
      - Suhrkamp Verlag, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 642)
      - Swiat Literacki, 1997 Jul 24 (Box 14, Folder 643)
    - To and From Martin Mooij
      - Moss, Stanley, 1994 Jan 2 (Box 14, Folder 644)
      - Unidentified, 1992 Dec 18 (Box 14, Folder 645)
    - To and From Shimon Peres
      - Kissinger, Henry, 1994 Jan 19 (Box 14, Folder 646)
        Photocopy of letter from Kissinger
      - Mitterand, François, 1993, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 647)
        Photocopies of letters
    - To and From Schocken Publishing House
      - B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundations, 1970 Sep 29 (Box 14, Folder 648)
      - Omski, Sarah, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 649)
      - Radday, Yehuda, 1997 Aug 5 (Box 14, Folder 650)
      - Unidentified, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 651)
    - Others
      - Akavia, Miriam to [Bibliophiles?] Press, 1995 Aug 2 (Box 14, Folder 652)
      - Aloni, Shulamit to Chinese Writers' Association, 1993 Feb 7 (Box 14, Folder 653)
      - American Poetry Review to Olwyn Hughes, 1983 Mar 22 (Box 14, Folder 654)
      - Arpaly, Boaz, to Universitat Tel Aviv, 1995 Feb 18 (Box 14, Folder 655)
      - Baum, Phil to Murray Greenfield, 1967 Apr 11 (Box 14, Folder 656)
      - Biderman, Chana to Harper & Row, 1986 Mar 24 (Box 14, Folder 657)
      - Boyle, Kay to Grace Schulman, 1982 Jun 12 (Box 14, Folder 658)
      - China Culture Newspaper to Israeli Embassy, China, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 659)
      - Coetzee, John to Christian Salmon, 1995 Feb 21 (Box 14, Folder 660)
      - [Dybek, Stuart?] to unidentified, 1993 Jul 11 (Box 14, Folder 661)
        Includes photocopy of article
      - Galbraith, John Kenneth to Thomas R. Pickering, 1986 Apr 1 (Box 14, Folder 662)
      - Golan, Shammai to Yehudit Vered, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 663)
      - Greenberg, Helen to Book Publishers Association of Israel, 1990 Nov 30 (Box 14, Folder 664)
      - Hessisches Literaturbüro im Mousonturm to "Frau" Krumpholz, 1998 May 26 (Box 14, Folder 665)
      - Israel. Shagrirut (Netherlands) to Devorah Ben David, 1988 Jul 28 (Box 14, Folder 666)
      - Jerusalem International Music Competitions to Gabriel Iranyi, 1997 Jul 1 (Box 14, Folder 667)
      - Kames, Peggy to unidentified, 1999 Nov 18 (Box 14, Folder 668)
      - Kemal, Yasar to Christian Salmon, 1995 Feb 13 (Box 14, Folder 669)
      - Kotlowitz, Robert to Frederick Sweet, 1974 Aug 21 (Box 14, Folder 670)
      - Kovenski, Idit to HarperCollins, 1995 Mar 8 (Box 14, Folder 671)
      - Maoz, [R.?] to Maariv, 1997 Feb 10 (Box 14, Folder 672)
      - Maynard, John to Jerome Shestack, 1984 Oct 29 (Box 14, Folder 673)
      - McHugh, Heather to Ted Solotaroff, 1983 Dec 14 (Box 14, Folder 674)
      - National Videograph to Harper & Row, 1974 Feb 26 (Box 14, Folder 675)
      - Penguin Books to Calmann & King, 1994 Nov 23 (Box 14, Folder 676)
      - Poetry Center of the 92nd Street YM-YWHA (New York, N.Y.) to B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundations, 1997 Mar 31 (Box 14, Folder 677)
      - R. Piper & Co. Verlag to Jacob Hessing, 1987 Aug 6 (Box 14, Folder 678)
      - Schechtman, Maty to Emanuel Hausman, 1989 Mar 13 (Box 14, Folder 679)
      - Smith, Diana Lilley to Lannan Foundation (Box 14, Folder 680)
      - South African Broadcasting Corporation to HarperCollins, 1993 Oct 12 (Box 14, Folder 681)
      - Sternberg, Sigmund to Robert Harris, 1994 Jun 15 (Box 14, Folder 682)
      - University of California, Berkeley to Victor Rosenberg, 1974 Oct 18 (Box 14, Folder 683)
      - Vickers, Sylvia to Sylvia Smith, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 684)
      - Wallmann, Jürgen Peter to Else Lasker-Schüler Gesellschaft, 1992 Sep 16 (Box 14, Folder 685)
      - Wheatcroft, John to Larry Shinn, 1986 Oct 13 (Box 14, Folder 686)
      - Unidentified to "Emanuela" [Amichai?], n.d. (Box 14, Folder 687)
      - Unidentified to "Gabriel", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 688)
      - Unidentified, 1986-99, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 689)
- Writings of Yehuda Amichai, 1952-1999; Series II; 8.97; (22 boxes)
  Series II, Writings of Yehuda Amichai, is organized into ten subseries: Articles and Essays; Children's Books; Forewords and Introductions; Interviews; Novels; Plays; Poetry; Speeches, Addresses, and Lectures; and Other Writings.
  - ARTICLES AND ESSAYS
    - [50 Years of Israel], drafts, holograph, 1997-1998 (Box 15, Folder 690)
    - "Agnon and I," typescript photocopy, translated by Jeremy Garber, 1978 Feb 17 (Box 15, Folder 691)
    - "Al hatsgat Kimat Shir Ahavah," draft, holograph, 1990 Feb 15 (Box 15, Folder 692)
    - "Be-yom shishi be-ganay..." draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 693)
    - "Chernikovsky," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 694)
    - "Every Man is Born a Poet," computer printout, [1987?] (Box 15, Folder 695)
    - "The Great Jewish Revolution," drafts, holograph and fax, corrected, 1995, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 696)
    - ["I write in Hebrew because..."], drafts, holograph, photocopies, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 697)
    - ["I'm a principle against..."], draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 698)
    - "Kan veahshav uve-yamim ha-aherim," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 699)
    - "Die Last doppelter Identität?" typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 700)
    - "Memories of Israel," drafts, holograph, corrected, and printed version, Diversion (3 copies), 1988 May (Box 15, Folder 701-702)
    - "ha-Mishak ve-ha-safa," printed version, ha-Shir ha-nakhon, photocopy, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 703)
    - "Mit der Vergangenheit Leben," printed version (9 copies), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 704)
    - "My City, My Neighborhood," drafts, holograph and computer printout, corrected, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 705)
    - "My Nation Lives," printed version, The New Republic, photocopy, 1998 May 11 (Box 15, Folder 706)
    - "New York Notes," printed version, Midstream, 1967 Nov (Box 15, Folder 707)
    - "Notes on Agnon," printed version, Midstream, 1967 Feb (Box 15, Folder 708)
    - "Postcards from Jerusalem," printed version, Midstream, 1968 Jan (Box 15, Folder 709)
    - "Reshimot Amerikaniyot," printed version, [1969?] (Box 15, Folder 710)
    - "Shene mine hazon," drafts, holograph (Box 15, Folder 711)
    - "Who are you, Ivan Schwebel?" offprint, Ariel (2 copies), 1973 (Box 15, Folder 712)
    - "Yoman," printed version, Moznayim (2 copies), 1969 (Box 15, Folder 713)
  - CHILDREN'S BOOKS
    - Mah she-karah le-Roni be-Nyu York
      - Drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 714)
    - ha-Peninah
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 715)
    - Sefer ha-Lailah ha-gadol
      - Draft fragments and notes, holograph (Box 15, Folder 716)
      - Drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 717-719)
      - Drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 720)
      - [Later] draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 721-722)
      - Draft, computer printout, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 723)
      - Foreword, English translation, typescript, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 724)
    - "Sefer yeladim sheni"
      - Preliminary sketches, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 725)
    - ha-Zanav ha-shamen shel ha-Numah
      - Drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 726-727)
      - Envelopes, 1987
  - FOREWORDS AND INTRODUCTIONS
    - [For book on Schwebel's paintings], notes and drafts, holograph (Box 17, Folder 728)
    - [For CNAC Magazine ], draft, holograph, corrected, photocopy, [1985-1986?] (Box 17, Folder 729)
    - [For Exiles at Home ], notes and drafts, holograph and holograph, photocopy, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 730)
    - [For Flowers of Perhaps ], printed version, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 731)
    - [For French translation of Amichai's poems], notes and draft, holograph (Box 17, Folder 732)
    - [For Open Eyed Landscape ], drafts, holograph, corrected, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 733)
    - [For Short Opening ], drafts, holograph, correcteed, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 734)
    - [For The Western Wall ], notes and drafts, holograph and computer printout, photocopy, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 735-738)
    - "Mavo le-sefer mikhteve ha-yeladim," notes and drafts, holograph (Box 17, Folder 739)
    - "Vorwort," draft, holograph, corrected, photocopy, n.d.
  - INTERVIEWS
    - "A Conversation with Yehuda Amichai," with Haim Chertok, printed version, Jewish Frontier, photocopy, 1985 Jun (Box 17, Folder 740)
    - "A Conversation with Yehuda Amichai," with Stan Sanvel and Earl Ingersoll, draft, typescript, [1984?] (Box 17, Folder 741)
    - [For the B.B.C.], notes, holograph, 1990 Dec (Box 17, Folder 742)
    - "Gespräch mit Jehuda Amichai..." with Ingrid Wiltmann, draft, computer printout, 1996 [Feb 7?] (Box 17, Folder 743)
    - "Interview with Yehuda Amichai," with Doron Weber, draft, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 744)
    - "Interview with Yehuda Amichai," draft, fax, photocopy, 1994 Jul 22 (Box 17, Folder 745)
    - "[Isrihot?] li-heyot Bel," with Dan Omer, printed version, photocopy, 1978 Jul (Box 17, Folder 746)
    - "Ki adam atah ve-el adam tashuv," computer printout, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 747)
    - "A Language of the Heart," draft, typescript, 1979 Sep 19 (Box 17, Folder 748)
    - "Las vetas del pasado," with Enrique Krauze, printed version, Vuelta, photocopy, 1990 Aug (Box 17, Folder 749)
    - "Yehuda Amichai..." with David Montenegro, printed version, The American Poetry Review, corrected, photocopy, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 750)
  - NOVELS
    - Lo me-akhshav, lo mi-kan
      - Galley proof, [1963?]
      - Book jacket, English translation (Vallentine, Mitchell ed.), [1973] (Box 17, Folder 751)
      - Publicity, German translation, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 752)
      - Reviews, German translation, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 753)
    - Untitled
      - Draft, holograph, [1965] (Box 17, Folder 754)
      - Drafts and draft fragments, holograph, [1970] (Box 17, Folder 755-756)
  - PLAYS
    - "Bells & Trains"
      - Program, typescript, photocopy, 1971 Jan 24 (Box 18, Folder 757)
    - The Day Martin Buber Was Buried
      - Printed version, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 758)
      - Publicity, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 759)
    - "Herzel"
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 760)
    - "Kemo shir ahavah"
      - Draft, computer printout, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 761)
      - Draft, English translation, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 762)
    - "Kenes ha-kitah"
      - Printed version, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 763)
    - La-harog oto
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 764)
      - Printed version (3 copies), n.d. (Box 18, Folder 765)
    - "Le-ehov bi-Yerushalayim"
      - Drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 766-767)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 768)
      - Printed version, French translation, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 769)
      - Printed version, German translation, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 770)
      - Printed version, Spanish translations, 1985, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 771-772)
    - "Masa le-Ninveh"
      - Draft, holograph, photocopy, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 773)
    - "Ninah me-Ashkelon"
      - Drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 774-775)
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 776)
      - Draft, holograph, photocopy, 1964 Jul 17 (Box 18, Folder 777)
      - Script, [typescript mimeograph?], n.d.
      - Draft, English translation, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 778)
      - Draft, English translation, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 779)
      - Outline for screenplay based on English translation, typescript, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 780)
    - "Pa amonim ve-rakavot"
      - Draft, typescript, [1974] (Box 19, Folder 781)
      - Draft, English translation, typescript and typescript carbon (Box 19, Folder 782)
      - Draft, English translation, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 783)
      - Draft, English translation, typescript, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 784)
      - Programs and publicity (Box 19, Folder 785)
      - Hungarian translation, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 786)
    - "Shetah shel hefker"
      - Typescript mimeograph, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 787)
    - Untitled radio play
      - Drafts, typescripts, [1968] (Box 19, Folder 788)
  - POETRY
    - Collections
      - Gam ha-egrof hayah pa am yad petuhah ve-etsbaot
        - Drafts, holograph, corrected, 1987-1989 (Box 19, Folder 790-793)
        - Drafts, holograph, corrected, 1987-1989 (Box 20, Folder 794-796)
        - [Later] drafts, holograph, corrected, [1989?] (Box 20, Folder 797-798)
        - Proof, corrected, [1989?] (Box 20, Folder 799)
        - Printed versions, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 800)
        - List of corrections, English translation, [1990-1991] (Box 20, Folder 801)
      - Lel shabat im meshorer Yehudah Amihai
        - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 802)
      - Love Poems
        - Proof, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 803)
      - Me-adam atah ve-el adam tashuv
        - Drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 804-805)
        - Clipping, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 806)
        - Drafts, corrected, and printed versions, English translations (Box 21, Folder 807)
        - Publicity, 1985 Nov (Box 21, Folder 808)
      - Me-ahore kol zeh mistater osher gadol
        - Drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 809-811)
        - Printed versions, 1973-1974 (Box 21, Folder 812)
      - "Mehevah li-Yehudah Amihai"
        - Draft, manuscript and photocopies, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 813)
      - Mi-shire Yehudah Amihai
        - Printed version, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 814)
      - Mivhar mi-tokh shire Yehudah Amihai
        - Printed version, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 815)
      - Mivhar shirim
        - Printed version, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 816)
      - Nof galui enayim
        - Drafts, holograph, corrected, [1991-1992?] (Box 21, Folder 817)
        - Drafts, German translation, typescript, 1991, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 818)
      - Patuah sagur patuah
        - [Early] drafts, holograph, corrected, 1991-1996, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 819-820)
        - [Early] drafts, holograph, corrected, 1991-1996, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 821-826)
        - [Early] drafts, holograph, corrected, 1991-1996, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 827-833)
        - [Later] drafts, holograph, corrected, 1996, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 834-835)
        - [Later] drafts, holograph, corrected, 1996, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 836-839)
        - Drafts, holograph, corrected, [1998?] (Box 24, Folder 840-842)
        - Proof, corrected, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 843)
        - Draft, English translation, typescript, corrected, with proofreaders' marks, photocopy, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 844)
        - Introduction, English translation, fax, 1999 Nov 10 (Box 24, Folder 845)
      - Shaat ha-hesed
        - Drafts, holograph, corrected, [1981-1982?] (Box 25, Folder 846-851)
          Includes notes from Chana Amichai
        - [Later] drafts, holograph, [1981-1982?] (Box 26, Folder 852-853)
        - Printed versions, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 854)
        - Draft, German translation, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 855)
      - Shalvah gedolah: sheelot u-teshuvot
        - [Early] drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 856-860)
        - [Later] drafts, holograph, corrected, [1979-1980] (Box 26, Folder 861-862)
      - Songs of Jerusalem and Myself
        - Dust jacket, [1973] (Box 27, Folder 863)
      - [ Temunah va-shir: tsiyurim mi-tokh sidrat ha-zahav ?]
        - Drafts, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 864)
      - Yehuda Amichai: A Life of Poetry, 1948-1984
        - Publicity, 1994 (Box 27, Folder 865)
      - Yerushalayim
        - Selected poems, printed version, photocopies, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 866)
      - ha-Zeman
        - Drafts, holograph, corrected, [1970?] (Box 27, Folder 867-868)
        - Drafts, English translations, holograph, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 869)
        - Drafts, English translations, typescript, corrected, with printer's annotations and proofreaders' marks, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 870)
        - Proof, "A Bird at Dawn is Singing," corrected, 1978 Sep 27
        - Proof, Master, 1st pass, English translation, corrected, 1978 Sep 30
        - Proof, Dupe, 1st pass, corrected, 1978 Sep 30
        - Proof, Master, 3rd pass, corrected, 1978 Nov 20 (Box 27, Folder 871)
        - Dust jacket, English translation, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 872)
        - Publicity, German translation, 1998 Feb (Box 27, Folder 873)
    - Individual poems
      - "1924," proof, English translation, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 874)
      - "Adam o Mekhinah tosit," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 875)
      - "Ahavah," drafts, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 876)
      - "Ahavah le-yad ha-yam," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 877)
      - "Ahavah rishon," draft, holograph (Box 27, Folder 878)
      - "Ahavat David," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 879)
      - "Akhsanyah," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 880)
      - "Alitalia," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 881)
      - "ha-Ananim," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 882)
      - "Ani ba-hof," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 883)
      - "Asinu," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 884)
      - "Asiyat ribah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 885)
      - "Atsmaut," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 886)
      - "Avi hayah arba shanim be-milhametam," draft, typescript, 1982 May 25 (Box 27, Folder 887)
      - "Avigail," drafts, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 888)
      - "Aviv," drafts, holograph, corrected, 1988, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 889)
      - "Aviv be-Ramlah," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 890)
      - ["Avyo"?], draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 891)
      - "Ba-derekh le-Hevron," draft, holograph (Box 27, Folder 892)
      - "Ba-etsaot li-feamim ehad," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 893)
      - "Ba-geshem la-derekh le-seker," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 894)
      - "Banot kuma..." draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 895)
      - "Bar Mitsvah," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 896)
      - "Batul," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 897)
      - "ha-Bayit she-mi-mul," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 898)
      - "Be-vet keneset," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 899)
      - "Be-dirat Ariyeh," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 900)
      - "Bedvi," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 901)
      - "Be-ir ha-atikah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 902)
      - "Be-kupah ha-tahanah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 903)
      - "Be-makom she-bo holhim ve-avim," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 904)
      - "Ben..." drafts, holograph, corrected (Box 28, Folder 905)
      - "Ben adam hu bayit," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 906)
      - ["Be-nes ten"?], draft, holograph, corrected (Box 28, Folder 907)
      - "Be-yamin Mosheh ba-erev," draft, holograph, corrected and printed version, photocopy (Box 28, Folder 908)
      - "Be-zavit yesharah," English translation, photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 909)
        Includes translation by Benjamin Harshav and essay, "On the Beginnings of Israeli Poetry and Yehuda Amichai's Quatrains"
      - "Bohen otha," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 910)
      - "Berakhah," draft, holograph, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 911)
      - "ha-Bushah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 912)
      - "Darkhe ahavah," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 913)
      - "ha-David halakh li-Kero kalah..." draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 914)